"Drink Shop"
Hokuto City, in Yamanashi Prefecture...
山梨県北杜市
Beyond the Koshu Highway at the bottom
of the hill from Hinoharu Station,
中央本線の日野春駅から伸びる下り坂は
甲州街道を越えるとゆるい登りになる
which is on the Chuo Main Line,
there is a gradual incline.
親はいない
I have no parents.
No money, either.
Nor do I have any hobbies,
お金もない
趣味もないし
anyone I can call a friend,
or any goals for the future.
友達と呼べる人も　将来の目標もない
そう… 私は…
Yes, I...
"Super Cub"
"Episode 1: The Girl with Nothing"
"2nd Year"
All right, good morning.
Let's see, any absences...?
は～い　おはようございます
え～っと　欠席は…
なしですね…
No, there aren't. Okay, then...
はい…っと
"That acts to connect"
They knew that they could go
anywhere with the motorcycle.
That's why they said happily
where to go tomorrow.
なぁ　昨日の夜のさぁ　番組見た？
Hey, did you see that show
last night? It was so good--
すげぇおもしろかった
"Chukadon"
You know what? I do nothing but
watch videos on the net every night,
ねぇねぇ　私毎晩ネット動画ばっかり見てるんだけどさ
and I found this girl I'm a big fan of.
推しの女の子見つけちゃった～
あのね　北海道…
Get this, she's in Hokkaido--
えっ
"Crea Scoopy"
Too much.
高っ…
"Monkey125"
Are you here shopping?
お客さんかい？
I thought I wanted a scooter, but it looks
like I don't have nearly enough money.
原付が欲しいと思ったんだけど
どうやらお金が全然足りないみたいです
Hmm, perhaps a used one will do.
中古でよければ
Huh?
Um, I really have no money.
あのぅ… 本当にお金が
It's 10,000 yen.
１万円
I'll... take it.
これ… 買います
Why is it only 10,000 yen?
なんで１万円なんですか？
Some people got killed.
人を…死なせてる
Three of them.
３人
I don't mind.
かまいません
Huh?
えっ？
I'll buy it.
買います
Come inside.
中へ
Fill out your name
and address here and here.
ここと…ここに住所と名前
"Koguma"
I don't... have a license.
免許…持ってません
"Motor Scooter Licensing"
The test questions never change.
試験問題はずっと変わってないから
Th-Thank you very much.
あ…ありがとうございました
Do you have a helmet and gloves?
ヘルメットとグローブは？
Yes, I brought them.
持ってきていますよ
あぁ…
Just a moment.
ちょっと待ってな
Here, take these.
ほい　これ
How many people did these kill?
これは何人殺してるんですか？
Hmm, they're brand new.
新品
"Bike-buying campaign!!"
They're running a promotion.
キャンペーンってやつ
"Free helmet & gloves with purchase!!!"
They're running a promotion.
Once you've put a hundred kilos on it,
bring it back for an oil change.
走行距離が100キロを超えたら　オイル交換しにきな
Doing so will extend the engine
life of these used ones.
中古はな　それでエンジンの寿命が延びるんだ
Okay.
はい
I'll put this in here for you.
これ　ここに入れとくから
Release the handlebar lock
and turn the key on.
ハンドルロック解除して　キーをオン
で　ペダルをキック
Then, give the pedal a kick.
All right.
わかりました
それじゃあかからないよ
You'll have to kick harder
than that to start it.
Those are the basics of how
it works. Now, give it a try.
基本操作はだいたいそんな感じ
じゃあやってみて
Before kicking, gradually move
the pedal with my foot...
キックの前に
足でペダルを小刻みに動かして
...and find the place
where it starts to push back.
踏みごたえのある位置を探して…
Put it in first gear...
ギアを一速へ
Thank you very much.
ありがとうございました
A keychain... I'll have to go
to the hardware store.
チェーンキーか…ホームセンターまでって…
Oh, yeah, on my Cub.
そっか…
カブで
I should hurry and get
so I can ride it better, huh?
早く乗れるようになったほうがいいよね
"Yamanashi-exclusive fine fruity sweets"
The convenience store at night...
夜のコンビニ…
"Yamanashi-exclusive fine fruity sweets"
Be strong.
我慢
Gradually move the pedal with my foot...
足でペダルを小刻みに動かして
...and find the place
where it starts to push back.
踏みごたえのある位置を探して…
えっ？
Why?
なんで？
What's wrong?
どうした？
えっ
Huh?
Are you not feeling okay, or something?
具合でも悪くなったのか？
Oh, no, I'm fine.
あ… 大丈夫です
Well, it's getting late.
Be careful heading home.
まぁ　もう遅いから　気をつけて帰れよ
あっ…はい
Oh, sure.
I'll put this in here for you.
これ　ここ入れとくから
"Owner's Manual"
"When the engine won't start"...
「エンジンが始動しないとき」
Page 89!
89ページ！
"Is there fuel in the gas tank?"
Gasoline...
ガソリン…
"Gasoline"
"Refuel" "Full"
The fuel petcock...
燃料コック…
"RES"...
RES…
"Reserve fuel"!
予備燃料！
"Remove the gas tank cap,
「燃料タンクのキャップを外して
and fill gasoline through the inlet to
the lower edge of the filler neck."
ガソリンを注入口の下側にある　レベルプレート下端まで」
I made it... home...
帰って…これた…
すれ違う風　未来に溶けてく
近づいてくる　優しいエンジンの音
透明だった世界に　車輪で色を付けよう
ともに駆け抜けた道
誰にも描けない私の絵になる
遠くで春が呼ぶ　すぐそこかもしれない
できるだけたくさんの　思い出連れてこう
一緒に過ごす日々　見つけた彩りは決して
色褪せない　いつだってずっと　そばにいるよ
Good.
よし
"Do not warm up the engine for too long."
「暖機運転　長時間はだめ」
Is that... long enough?
もう…いいかな
It costs just over 500 yen
to fill the tank.
ガソリン満タンで500円ちょっと
On the Chuo Main Line, that would
be about enough to get to Kofu.
中央本線なら　甲府ぐらいまで行けるかな
Up until yesterday,
I didn't have anything.
昨日まで　私には何もなかった
But... starting today, I have my Cub.
けど　今日からはカブがある
I wonder how far my Cub will take me.
このカブは　どこまで走れるんだろう？
"Reiko"
"Super Cub Episode 2"
Episode 2: "Reiko."
第２話　「礼子」